<Namespace Name="System.Web.ClientServices">
  <Docs>
    <summary>The <see cref="N:System.Web.ClientServices" /> namespace provides classes that support access in Windows-based applications to the Microsoft Ajax authentication, roles, and profiles services.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 The classes in the <xref:System.Web.ClientServices> namespace support the client application service providers in the <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.Providers> namespace. These service providers enable Windows-based applications to use the [!INCLUDE[ajax_current_short](~/includes/ajax-current-short-md.md)] authentication, roles, and profiles services through existing [!INCLUDE[dnprdnlong](~/includes/dnprdnlong-md.md)] membership, identity, and application settings infrastructures. The client service providers also support occasional connectivity by storing and retrieving user information in a local data cache when the application is offline. For more information, see [Client Application Services](~/docs/framework/common-client-technologies/client-application-services.md).  
  
 The <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.ClientFormsIdentity> and <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.ClientRolePrincipal> classes provide properties and methods related to a user's identity, role, and authentication state.  
  
 The <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.ConnectivityStatus> class enables you to store the status of the user's network connection in the local data cache. The connectivity status indicates whether the client service providers will use the offline cache or attempt to access the application services.  
  
> [!NOTE]
>  The <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.ConnectivityStatus> class contains no logic to determine the actual status of the network connection. You are responsible for determining the connectivity status of your application according to your own criteria and setting the <xref:System.Web.ClientServices.ConnectivityStatus.IsOffline%2A> property accordingly. For example, Windows-based applications often provide an option in the user interface so that users can work in offline mode or attempt to go online.  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
  </Docs>
</Namespace>