<Namespace Name="System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures">
  <Docs>
    <summary>Provides classes to describe the structure of an <see cref="T:System.Windows.Xps.Packaging.XpsDocument" /> in terms of sections, paragraphs, figures, bulleted or numbered lists, and tables.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 The formatting and layout of an [!INCLUDE[TLA2#tla_xps](~/includes/tla2sharptla-xps-md.md)] document enables different parts of the content to behave in a semantic form such as in paragraphs, tables, and lists.  Humans can perceive the semantic structure of the content from its appearance; but the physical format and layout of the markup does not explicitly identify the actual semantic elements.  To enable programmatic understanding of the document organization, the <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures> namespace provides structure elements that can be used to define the document by its semantic parts.  
  
 Each page of an [!INCLUDE[TLA2#tla_xps](~/includes/tla2sharptla-xps-md.md)] document contains a <xref:System.Windows.Documents.FixedPage> element that defines its *content* in the form of positional text runs and graphics.  Through the use of document structure elements, pages of an [!INCLUDE[TLA2#tla_xps](~/includes/tla2sharptla-xps-md.md)] document can also be associated with <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures.StoryFragment> elements that define the *structure* of the page in the form of sections, paragraphs, lists, figures, and tables.  The <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures.NamedElement> class is used to define the associations between content and structure parts of the document markup.  A <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures.NamedElement> is the child of a structural element, such as a table cell or bullet list item that is located in the <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures.StoryFragment> hierarchy of a page.  A <xref:System.Windows.Documents.DocumentStructures.NamedElement> identifies an item in the <xref:System.Windows.Documents.FixedPage> hierarchy of the same page.  The item it refers to is the content of the structural element.  
  
 Applications that create [!INCLUDE[TLA2#tla_xps](~/includes/tla2sharptla-xps-md.md)] documents are not required to include structural markup, but use of document structure elements enhances the flexibility by which applications can access and use the content of a document.  
  
 For more information about structure elements of [!INCLUDE[TLA2#tla_xps](~/includes/tla2sharptla-xps-md.md)] documents, see Chapter 9 and Appendix E of the XML Paper Specification (XPS) available for download at [http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=67000](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=67000).  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
    <altmember cref="N:System.Windows.Documents" />
    <altmember cref="N:System.Windows.Xps" />
  </Docs>
</Namespace>