<Namespace Name="System.Printing">
  <Docs>
    <summary>Provides classes that enable you to automate the management of print servers, print queues, and print jobs.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 This namespace contains the following core classes:  
  
-   The <xref:System.Printing.PrintSystemObject> class, which is the base class for the other core printing classes.  
  
-   The <xref:System.Printing.PrintServer> class, which represents an actual print server, usually a computer.  
  
-   The <xref:System.Printing.PrintQueue> class, which represents an actual print queue and its printer.  
  
-   The <xref:System.Printing.PrintSystemJobInfo> class, which represents a particular print job.  
  
-   The <xref:System.Printing.PrintTicket> class, which instructs the printer how to process a print job.  
  
 Classes derived from the <xref:System.Printing.PrintSystemObject> class each have a <xref:System.Printing.PrintSystemObject.Commit%2A> and a <xref:System.Printing.PrintSystemObject.Refresh%2A> method. You must use these methods to ensure that instances of the classes are synchronized with the hardware or software components that they represent.  
  
 The <xref:System.Printing> namespace also includes many enumerations that describe printer capabilities, such as whether a printer can produce collated output, and that specify instructions to printers, such as the paper size to use for a print job.  
  
 This namespace is part of the enhanced printing services provided with Windows Presentation Foundation. Managed code developers using Windows Forms must use the APIs in the <xref:System.Drawing.Printing> namespace.  
  
> [!CAUTION]
>  Classes within the <xref:System.Printing> namespace are not supported for use within a Windows service or ASP.NET application or service. Attempting to use these classes from within one of these application types may produce unexpected problems, such as diminished service performance and run-time exceptions.  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
    <altmember cref="T:System.Windows.Controls.PrintDialog" />
    <altmember cref="N:System.Printing.Interop" />
    <altmember cref="N:System.Printing.IndexedProperties" />
    <altmember cref="N:System.Windows.Xps" />
    <altmember cref="N:System.Windows.Documents" />
  </Docs>
</Namespace>