<Namespace Name="System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement">
  <Docs>
    <summary>The <see cref="N:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement" /> namespace provides uniform access and manipulation of user, computer, and group security principals across the multiple principal stores: Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS), Active Directory Lightweight Directory Services (AD LDS), and Machine SAM (MSAM). <see cref="N:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement" /> manages directory objects independent of the <see cref="N:System.DirectoryServices" /> namespace.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 Managed directory services applications can take advantage of the <xref:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement> API to simplify management of user, computer and group principals. Solutions that previously required intricate knowledge of the store or lengthy code, such as finding all groups to which a user belongs, are accomplished in a few lines of code with the <xref:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement> API.  
  
 The following features are available on the <xref:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement> API:  
  
-   Basic directory operations such as creating and updating security principals is simplified. The application requires less knowledge of the underlying stores to perform these operations.  
  
-   Applications can extend the object model to include new types of directory objects.  
  
-   Account management tasks, such as enabling and disabling a user account, are simplified.  
  
-   Cross-store support allows group objects in the Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS), Active Directory Lightweight Directory Services (AD LDS), and Machine SAM (MSAM) databases to contain members from different types of stores.  
  
-   Query by example searching, available on the <xref:System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement.PrincipalSearcher> class, enables applications to set properties on a principal object and search the selected store for other objects that contain matching property values.  
  
-   Enhanced search on computer, user and group principal objects enables applications to search the selected store for matching principal objects.  
  
-   Recursive search, available on the group principal object, enables applications to search a group recursively and return only principal objects that are leaf nodes.  
  
-   Credential validation against the Machine SAM, AD DS, and AD LS stores is simplified.  
  
-   Connections speeds are increased by using the Fast Concurrent Bind (FSB) feature when available. Connection caching decreases the number of ports used.  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
    <altmember cref="N:System.DirectoryServices" />
    <related type="Article" href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/9255c42d-04a6-4727-adf1-bad9e42fa92a">System.DirectoryServices.AccountManagement Namespace Overview</related>
  </Docs>
</Namespace>