<Namespace Name="System.Transactions">
  <Docs>
    <summary>The <see cref="N:System.Transactions" /> namespace contains classes that allow you to write your own transactional application and resource manager. Specifically, you can create and participate in a transaction (local or distributed) with one or multiple participants.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
  
 The `System.Transactions` infrastructure makes transactional programming simple and efficient throughout the platform by supporting transactions initiated in SQL Server, ADO.NET, MSMQ, and the Microsoft Distributed Transaction Coordinator (MSDTC). It provides both an explicit programming model based on the <xref:System.Transactions.Transaction> class, as well as an implicit programming model using the <xref:System.Transactions.TransactionScope> class, in which transactions are automatically managed by the infrastructure. It is highly recommended that you use the easier implicit model for development. To get started, see the [Implementing An Implicit Transaction Using Transaction Scope](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.0/ms172152(v=vs.85)) topic. For more information on writing a transactional application, see [Writing A Transactional Application](~/docs/framework/data/transactions/writing-a-transactional-application.md).
  
 `System.Transactions` also provides types for you to implement a resource manager. The transaction manager native to the `System.Transactions` infrastructure allows volatile resources or a single durable resource enlistment to commit or roll back efficiently. For more information on implementing a resource manager, see [Implementing A Resource Manager](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/81509719-d579-4530-831e-42e1acdef63e).  
  
 The transaction manager also transparently escalates local transactions to distributed transactions by coordinating through a disk-based transaction manager like the DTC, when an additional durable resource manager enlists itself with a transaction. There are two key ways that the `System.Transactions` infrastructure provides enhanced performance.  
  
-   Dynamic Escalation, which means that the `System.Transactions` infrastructure only engages the MSDTC when it is actually required for a transaction. This area is covered in depth in the [Transaction Management Escalation](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/5b87ae58-8ccf-4b9b-9715-41e4aade89b7) topic.  
  
-   Promotable Enlistments, which allows a resource, such as a database, to take ownership of the transaction if it is the only entity participating in the transaction. Later, if needed, the `System.Transactions` infrastructure can still escalate the management of the transaction to MSDTC. This further reduces the chance of using the MSDTC. This area is covered in depth in the [Optimization Using Single Phase Commit and Promotable Single Phase Notification](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.0/ms229980(v=vs.85)) topic.  
  
 `System.Transactions` defines three levels of trust that restrict access on the types of resources it exposes. Specifically, the *System.Transactions* assembly can be called by partially trusted code as it has been marked with the `AllowPartiallyTrustedCallers` attribute (APTCA). This attribute essentially removes the implicit <xref:System.Security.Permissions.SecurityAction.LinkDemand> for the `FullTrust` permission set that is otherwise automatically placed on each publicly accessible method in each type. However, some types and members still require stronger permissions.  
  
 The following is a list of types and members that are not callable by partially trusted code because they are decorated with the following declarative security attribute:  
  
 `PermissionSetAttribute(SecurityAction.LinkDemand, Name := "FullTrust")`  
  
 System.Transactions.Transaction.EnlistDurable  
  
 System.Transactions.Transaction.EnlistPromotableSinglePhase  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionInterop  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionManager.DistributedTransactionStarted  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionManager.HostCurrentTransactionCallback  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionManager.Reenlist  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionManager.RecoveryComplete  
  
 System.Transactions.TransactionScope.TransactionScope (System.Transactions.Transaction,System.TimeSpan,System.Transactions.EnterpriseServicesInteropOption)  
  
 M:System.Transactions.TransactionScope.TransactionScope(System.Transactions.TransactionScopeOption,System.Transactions.TransactionOptions,System.Transactions.EnterpriseServicesInteropOption)  
  
 For more information on the various trust levels, see [Security Trust Levels in Accessing Resources](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/8e45acbc-0d81-4f64-9da7-8f766aebff51).  
  
 Core Development Technologies\Data Access\Transaction Processing\  
  
 For more information on how to use the `System.Transactions` namespace, you can consult the conceptual documentation [Transaction Processing](https://docs.microsoft.com/previous-versions/dotnet/netframework-3.0/w97s6fw4(v=vs.85)), located under the "Core Development Technologies\Data Access\Transaction Processing\\" section in the documentation. Specifically, you can find more information in the following topics.  
  
 [Features Provided By System.Transactions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/99cc5ce0-b7fd-4d78-a553-a3dd3f17ed45)  
  
 [Implementing A Resource Manager](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/81509719-d579-4530-831e-42e1acdef63e)  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
  </Docs>
</Namespace>