<Type Name="IDestinationTypeProvider" FullName="System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider">
  <TypeSignature Language="C#" Value="public interface IDestinationTypeProvider" />
  <TypeSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".class public interface auto ansi abstract IDestinationTypeProvider" />
  <TypeSignature Language="DocId" Value="T:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider" />
  <TypeSignature Language="VB.NET" Value="Public Interface IDestinationTypeProvider" />
  <TypeSignature Language="C++ CLI" Value="public interface class IDestinationTypeProvider" />
  <TypeSignature Language="F#" Value="type IDestinationTypeProvider = interface" />
  <AssemblyInfo>
    <AssemblyName>System.Xaml</AssemblyName>
    <AssemblyVersion>4.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
  </AssemblyInfo>
  <Interfaces />
  <Docs>
    <summary>Represents a service that can return a CLR type system identifier for the destination type. The destination type is relevant when the destination type for a property-setting operation is indirectly reported by reflection or other mechanisms.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 The type that is returned by <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType%2A> is resolved from the current position of the XAML node stream by using current XAML schema context.  
  
 If you use the XAML type system as implemented by .NET Framework XAML Services and access the service context under these conditions, <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType%2A> returns the <xref:System.Xaml.XamlType.UnderlyingType%2A> based on available XAML type system information and CLR-based XAML schema context.  
  
 This service is relevant for situations where pure CLR reflection or other mechanisms might not provide enough information about a destination type. The following is a list of some relevant scenarios for <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider>:  
  
-   The CLR type system reports an indirect type because of how the CLR defines and uses types, and you want a true destination type. For example, the APIs in .NET Framework XAML Services use this service internally when they process event members. Events are reported by pure CLR reflection as a <xref:System.Delegate>.  
  
-   You want to ensure that the destination type of a type converter usage matches the expected type that the type converter can produce. This scenario is useful when the destination type is parameterized or generic.  
  
-   Your value converter is being called from a usage that nested in another value converter. In this case, <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType%2A> unwinds the nesting and returns the destination type of the actual property being set, instead of returning the output type of any intervening value converter.  
  
 Type converters and markup extensions can query for <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider> as a service on the service context that is provided by a XAML object writer, when the XAML object writer invokes value conversion behavior. For more information, see [Type Converters and Markup Extensions for XAML](~/docs/framework/xaml-services/type-converters-and-markup-extensions-for-xaml.md) and [Service Contexts Available to Type Converters and Markup Extensions](~/docs/framework/xaml-services/service-contexts-available-to-type-converters-and-markup-extensions.md).  
  
 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
    <altmember cref="T:System.Xaml.XamlObjectWriter" />
    <related type="Article" href="https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/db07a952-05ce-4aa4-b6f9-aac7397d0326">Type Converters or Markup Extensions for XAML</related>
  </Docs>
  <Members>
    <Member MemberName="GetDestinationType">
      <MemberSignature Language="C#" Value="public Type GetDestinationType ();" />
      <MemberSignature Language="ILAsm" Value=".method public hidebysig newslot virtual instance class System.Type GetDestinationType() cil managed" />
      <MemberSignature Language="DocId" Value="M:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType" />
      <MemberSignature Language="VB.NET" Value="Public Function GetDestinationType () As Type" />
      <MemberSignature Language="C++ CLI" Value="public:&#xA; Type ^ GetDestinationType();" />
      <MemberSignature Language="F#" Value="abstract member GetDestinationType : unit -&gt; Type" Usage="iDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType " />
      <MemberType>Method</MemberType>
      <AssemblyInfo>
        <AssemblyName>System.Xaml</AssemblyName>
        <AssemblyVersion>4.0.0.0</AssemblyVersion>
      </AssemblyInfo>
      <ReturnValue>
        <ReturnType>System.Type</ReturnType>
      </ReturnValue>
      <Parameters />
      <Docs>
        <summary>Returns the CLR <see cref="T:System.Type" /> that identifies the destination type for the relevant type converter or markup extension.</summary>
        <returns>A CLR <see cref="T:System.Type" /> value for the destination type.</returns>
        <remarks>
          <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 This method has no input parameter. What to return (and whether to return anything other than `null`) is determined by the current node position in the XAML node stream.  
  
## Service Implementers  
 If you reimplement this service, the <xref:System.Xaml.IDestinationTypeProvider.GetDestinationType%2A> method should return the type that a markup extension or type converter expects to check against its most specific conversion or output type.  
  
 ]]></format>
        </remarks>
      </Docs>
    </Member>
  </Members>
</Type>